Guide to the Leverich Family Papers 1817-1937 (Bulk 1820-1890) MS 381
New-York Historical Society
- Series I: Correspondence, 1825-1890, 1937
  - Subseries 1: Leverich & Co., 1838-1880
    Most of the material in the subseries concerns the post-bellum cotton business in New York and in the South, particularly Winnsboro, South Carolina, Norfolk, Virginia, and New Orleans. The principal correspondents in Winnsboro are James Aiken, H. L. Elliott, and James Chapman. The principal correspondents in New Orleans are William E. Leverich, brother of Henry S. and Charles P. Leverich, and J. T. Doswell. R. M. Doswell addresses correspondence from both New Orleans and Norfolk. Other correspondents include Henry Cobia and Lesesne & Wells, of Charleston, South Carolina, Duff Green & Son of Vicksburg, Mississippi, and George T. Rogers & Sons of Macon, Georgia. Specific subjects include weather conditions, overseas and domestic markets, prices, and credit. William E. Leverich's correspondence of the 1870's includes discussions of the Oak Lawn plantation and the Porters. Material from George Green & Son of Liverpool involves the cotton trade in Great Britain.
    The earlier letter book of Leverich & Co. dates from 1838 to 1841. This particular volume is attributed to Leverich & Co., rather than to a specific partner, because both Henry S. and Charles P. Leverich used it; letter books used by only one partner are attributed to that partner only. Most of the letters in the volume are to persons or firms in New Orleans. These include: J.H. Leverich & Co., a firm founded by James H. Leverich, a brother of Henry S. and Charles P. Leverich; William E. Leverich; Carriere, Darant & Co.; James Colles; Georges Legendere; and T.R. Hyde & Co. Frequent correspondents in other cities include Edward Dawson of Mobile, and Jackson & Todd of Philadelphia. Most of this material has to do with the sugar or cotton trades.
    The later letter books and the telegram books date from the 1870's. One of the letter books contains, in its entirety, letters to James Aiken. This volume is chiefly written in the hands of Edward Leverich, son of Henry Leverich, and Charles D. Leverich, son of Charles P. Leverich, and deals with cotton purchases and prices, and credit. The other later letter book is a letterpress book of bills. The telegram books contain messages to a variety of recipients, including James Aiken and H.L. Elliott. These are usually buy or sell orders, or price quotations. The 1875-1876 volume appears to contain some entries that may not be actual messages, but records of transactions that were simply entered in this particular volume. Two code books for deciphering transcripted messages are also included in this subseries.
    The overwhelming majority of the material in the Leverich & Co. sub-series dates from the Reconstruction period, and some correspondents refer to political events, especially in the South. James Aiken provided information on elections, race relations, and public opinion in Winnsboro. William E. Leverich provided the same type of information regarding New Orleans, including a description of the White League uprising in New Orleans in September 1874. Thomas J. Foster, an employee of Leverich & Co., described a racial disturbance in St. Mary's Parish that took place during the same month.
    - Letters received: A, 1865-1876 (Offsite-box 1, Folder 1)
    - Letters received: B, 1857-1859, 1865-1878 (Offsite-box 1, Folder 2)
    - Letters received: C, 1841, 1860, 1865-1878 (Offsite-box 1, Folder 3)
    - Letters received: D, 1849, 1857-1877 (Offsite-box 1, Folder 4)
    - Letters received: E, 1867-1876 (Offsite-box 1, Folder 5)
    - Letters received: F, 1860, 1865-1877 (Offsite-box 1, Folder 6)
    - Letters received: G, 1865-1876 (Offsite-box 1, Folder 7)
    - Letters received: H, 1855, 1865-1877 (Offsite-box 1, Folder 8)
    - Letters received: I, 1866, 1869-1870, 1877 (Offsite-box 1, Folder 9)
    - Letters received: J, 1865-1872, 1876 (Offsite-box 1, Folder 10)
    - Letters received: K, 1865-1876 (Offsite-box 1, Folder 11)
    - Letters received: L, 1865-1880 (Offsite-box 1, Folder 12)
    - Letters received: M, 1859-1877 (Offsite-box 2, Folder 1)
    - Letters received: N, 1865-1876 (Offsite-box 2, Folder 2)
    - Letters received: O, 1863-1876 (Offsite-box 2, Folder 3)
    - Letter received: P, Q, 1860, 1865-1877 (Offsite-box 2, Folder 4)
    - Letters received: R, 1859, 1865-1877 (Offsite-box 2, Folder 5)
    - Letters received: S, 1865-1877 (Offsite-box 2, Folder 6)
    - Letters received: T, 1867-1876 (Offsite-box 2, Folder 7)
    - Letters received: U, V, 1858-1859, 1865-1869 (Offsite-box 2, Folder 8)
    - Letters received: W, 1865-1878 (Offsite-box 2, Folder 9)
    - Letters received: Y, Z, 1860, 1868-1872 (Offsite-box 2, Folder 10)
    - Letters received: Unknown Correspondents, 1872 (Offsite-box 2, Folder 11)
    - Letters received: Aiken, J.D., 1868-1869, 1872 (Offsite-box 3, Folder 1)
    - Letters received: Aiken, James R., 1867 (Offsite-box 3, Folder 2)
    - Letters received: Aiken, James R., 1868 (Offsite-box 3, Folder 3)
    - Letters received: Aiken, James R., 1869 (Offsite-box 3, Folder 4)
    - Letters received: Aiken, James R., 1870 (Offsite-box 3, Folder 5)
    - Letters received: Aiken, James R., 1870-1871 (Offsite-box 3, Folder 6)
    - Letters received: Aiken, James R., 1871-1872 (Offsite-box 3, Folder 7)
    - Letters received: Aiken, James R., 1872-1875, undated (Offsite-box 3, Folder 8)
    - Letters received: Aiken, W.E., 1867-1875 (Offsite-box 4, Folder 1)
    - Letters received: Bacot & Co., 1869-1873, 1877 (Offsite-box 4, Folder 2)
    - Letters received: Barnwell, Arthur &Co., 1874-1878 (Offsite-box 4, Folder 3)
    - Letters received: Bratton, John, 1868-1873 (Offsite-box 4, Folder 4)
    - Letters received: Bremer, G & Co., 1868-1869 (Offsite-box 4, Folder 5)
    - Letters received: Brown & Clark, 1873 (Offsite-box 4, Folder 6)
    - Letters received: Budd & Blake, 1867-1869 (Offsite-box 4, Folder 7)
    - Letters received: Chapman, Fraser & Tylee, 1867-1871 (Offsite-box 4, Folder 8)
    - Letters received: Chapman, James, 1868 (Offsite-box 4, Folder 9)
    - Letters received: Chapman, James, 1869-1870 (Offsite-box 4, Folder 10)
    - Letters received: Chapman, Robert, 1867-1868 (Offsite-box 4, Folder 11)
    - Letters received: Cobia, Henry & Co., 1866-1871 (Offsite-box 4, Folder 12)
    - Letters received: Cohen, Hanckel & Co., 1869-1871 (Offsite-box 4, Folder 13)
    - Letters received: Collins, A. Lewis, 1866-1867 (Offsite-box 4, Folder 14)
    - Letters received: Conant and Rand, 1868-1870 (Offsite-box 4, Folder 15)
    - Letters received: Copeland and Bearden, 1869-1871 (Offsite-box 4, Folder 16)
    - Letters received: Cozzens, William C., 1865-1868 (Offsite-box 4, Folder 17)
    - Letters received: Creight, W. B., 1868-1873, 1877 (Offsite-box 4, Folder 18)
    - Letters received: Davies, Richard, 1865-1869 (Offsite-box 5, Folder 1)
    - Letters received: Davis, C. B., 1865-1878 (Offsite-box 5, Folder 2)
    - Letters received: Davis, S. M., 1869-1878 (Offsite-box 5, Folder 3)
    - Letters received: Dolton, William & Co., 1868-1870, 1876 (Offsite-box 5, Folder 4)
    - Letters received: Doswell, J. T., 1869-1870 (Offsite-box 5, Folder 5)
    - Letters received: Doswell, J. T., 1871-1875 (Offsite-box 5, Folder 6)
    - Letters received: Doswell, R. M., 1871-1873 (Offsite-box 5, Folder 7)
    - Letters received: Doswell, R. M., 1874-1877 (Offsite-box 5, Folder 8)
    - Letters received: Duncan, Henry P., 1867, 1876-1878 (Offsite-box 5, Folder 9)
    - Letters received: Duncan, Stephen Jr., 1865-1877 (Offsite-box 5, Folder 10)
    - Letters received: Dupuy, Charles L. C., 1872-1873 (Offsite-box 5, Folder 11)
    - Letters received: Elliott, H. L. & Co., 1866-1867 (Offsite-box 5, Folder 12)
    - Letters received: Elliott, H. L. & Co., 1868 (Offsite-box 5, Folder 13)
    - Letters received: Elliott, H. L., 1869 (Offsite-box 6, Folder 1)
    - Letters received: Elliott, H. L., 1871 (Offsite-box 6, Folder 2)
    - Letters received: Elliott, H. L., 1872 (Offsite-box 6, Folder 3)
    - Letters received: Elliott, H. L., 1873 (Offsite-box 6, Folder 4)
    - Letters received: Elliott, H. L., 1874 (Offsite-box 6, Folder 5)
    - Letters received: Elliott, H. L., 1875-1878 (Offsite-box 6, Folder 6)
    - Letters received: Foster & Levy, 1875-1878 (Offsite-box 6, Folder 7)
    - Letters received: Foster, Thomas J., 1871-1876 (Offsite-box 6, Folder 8)
    - Letters received: Green, Duff & Co., 1865-1866 (Offsite-box 6, Folder 9)
    - Letters received: Green, George & Son, 1865-1869 (Offsite-box 6, Folder 10)
    - Letters received: Green, George & Son, 1871-1873 (Offsite-box 6, Folder 11)
    - Letters received: Habersham, William, 1868-1870 (Offsite-box 7, Folder 1)
    - Letters received: Heilbuth, E., 1867 (Offsite-box 7, Folder 2)
    - Letters received: Hinde & Porter, 1866-1867 (Offsite-box 7, Folder 3)
    - Letters received: Hine, T. D., 1872, 1876 (Offsite-box 7, Folder 4)
    - Letters received: Hobart, E. & Co., 1874-1876 (Offsite-box 7, Folder 5)
    - Letters received: Hobson, Richard & Co., 1875-1876 (Offsite-box 7, Folder 6)
    - Letters received: Hope, Edward, 1870-1872 (Offsite-box 7, Folder 7)
    - Letters received: Irwin and Sloan, 1865 (Offsite-box 7, Folder 8)
    - Letters received: Johnston, J. M., 1865-1871 (Offsite-box 7, Folder 9)
    - Letters received: Jordan, Thomas, 1869-1872 (Offsite-box 7, Folder 10)
    - Letters received: Kennedy, S. H., 1870-1873 (Offsite-box 7, Folder 11)
    - Letters received: Kennett, W. C., 1866-1870 (Offsite-box 7, Folder 12)
    - Letters received: Lafitte, Edward, 1870-1871 (Offsite-box 7, Folder 13)
    - Letters received: Lafitte, Doswell & Co., 1870-1871 (Offsite-box 7, Folder 14)
    - Letters received: Le Forestier & Fils, 1867-1870 (Offsite-box 7, Folder 15)
    - Letters received: Lesesne & Wells, 1869-1873 (Offsite-box 7, Folder 16)
    - Letters received: Leverich, A. J., 1869-1870 (Offsite-box 7, Folder 17)
    - Letters received: Leverich, Annie M., 1873, 1874 (Offsite-box 7, Folder 18)
    - Letters received: Leverich, Charles D., 1866-1874 (Offsite-box 7, Folder 19)
    - Letters received: Leverich, Charles E., 1867-1868 (Offsite-box 7, Folder 20)
    - Letters received: Leverich, Charles E., 1869 (Offsite-box 8, Folder 1)
    - Letters received: Leverich, Charles E., 1869-1870 (Offsite-box 8, Folder 2)
    - Letters received: Leverich, Charles P., 1869 (Offsite-box 8, Folder 3)
    - Letters received: Leverich, Edward, 1869-1871, 1874 (Offsite-box 8, Folder 4)
    - Letters received: Leverich, Henry S., 1867-1874 (Offsite-box 8, Folder 5)
    - Letters received: Leverich, James H., 1876 (Offsite-box 8, Folder 6)
    - Letters received: Leverich, S.[tephen] D.[uncan], 1873 (Offsite-box 8, Folder 7)
    - Letters received: Leverich, William E., 1865-1869 (Offsite-box 8, Folder 8)
    - Letters received: Leverich, William E., 1870 (Offsite-box 8, Folder 9)
    - Letters received: Leverich, William E., 1871 (Offsite-box 8, Folder 10)
    - Letters received: Leverich, William E., 1873 (Offsite-box 8, Folder 11)
    - Letters received: Leverich, William E. (1 of 2), 1874 (Offsite-box 8, Folder 12)
    - Letters received: Leverich, William E. (2 of 2), 1874 (Offsite-box 8, Folder 13)
    - Letters received: Leverich, William E., 1875 (Offsite-box 8, Folder 14)
    - Letters received: Leverich, William E., 1876 (Offsite-box 9, Folder 1)
    - Letters received: Leverich, William E., 1877-1878 (Offsite-box 9, Folder 2)
    - Letters received: Lewes, Packham, 1868 (Offsite-box 9, Folder 3)
    - Letters received: Lowndes & Co., 1867-1868 (Offsite-box 9, Folder 4)
    - Letters received: Lowndes, C. T., 1869-1874 (Offsite-box 9, Folder 5)
    - Letters received: Mandeville, George S., 1865-1866 (Offsite-box 9, Folder 6)
    - Letters received: Matthews, John P., Jr., 1870 (Offsite-box 9, Folder 7)
    - Letters received: McConnell, J. M., 1871-1876 (Offsite-box 9, Folder 8)
    - Letters received: McMurran, Mary L., 1873-1876 (Offsite-box 9, Folder 9)
    - Letters received: Mercer, W. Newton, 1865 (Offsite-box 9, Folder 10)
    - Letters received: Miller, Walter T., 1871, 1873, 1876-1878 (Offsite-box 9, Folder 11)
    - Letters received: Minor, F. O., 1871, 1875 (Offsite-box 9, Folder 12)
    - Letters received: Minor, H. C., 1865, 1871, 1874-1877 (Offsite-box 9, Folder 13)
    - Letters received: Minor, K. S., 1866, 1868, 1870-1877 (Offsite-box 9, Folder 14)
    - Letters received: Newman, Charles, 1865-1866 (Offsite-box 9, Folder 15)
    - Letters received: Page, S. Davis, 1872, 1876-1878 (Offsite-box 9, Folder 16)
    - Letters received: Payne, George E., 1865-1866, 1870-1871, 1873 (Offsite-box 9, Folder 17)
    - Letters received: Peters, Edward D. & Co., 1868-1869 (Offsite-box 9, Folder 18)
    - Letters received: Peters & Reed, 1875-1876 (Offsite-box 9, Folder 19)
    - Letters received: Phillips' Provision Exchange, 1868 (Offsite-box 9, Folder 20)
    - Letters received: Pike, Lapeyre & Brother, 1865-1868 (Offsite-box 9, Folder 21)
    - Letters received: Pike, Brother & Co., 1869-1876 (Offsite-box 10, Folder 1)
    - Letters received: Porter, Annie, 1871 (Offsite-box 10, Folder 2)
    - Letters received: Porter, Mary, 1868-1870 (Offsite-box 10, Folder 3)
    - Letters received: Price, Hine & Tupper, 1866, 1871-1872 (Offsite-box 10, Folder 4)
    - Letters received: Reynolds Brothers, 1864, 1869-1876 (Offsite-box 10, Folder 5)
    - Letters received: Rogers, George T. & Sons, 1865-1871 (Offsite-box 10, Folder 6)
    - Letters received: Rondeau, C. A. F., 1859, 1872-1877 (Offsite-box 10, Folder 7)
    - Letters received: Roth, Johannes, 1869-1870 (Offsite-box 10, Folder 8)
    - Letters received: Ruff and Lauhow, 1867 (Offsite-box 10, Folder 9)
    - Letters received: St. John, Newton, 1871 (Offsite-box 10, Folder 10)
    - Letters received: Sands & Co., 1865 (Offsite-box 10, Folder 11)
    - Letters received: Shepard, A. D., 1865-1866 (Offsite-box 10, Folder 12)
    - Letters received: Shields, G. B., 1870-1875 (Offsite-box 10, Folder 13)
    - Letters received: Smith, Homer H. & Co., 1867, 1871-1876 (Offsite-box 10, Folder 14)
    - Letters received: Stanard, McColl & Co., 1874 (Offsite-box 10, Folder 15)
    - Letters received: Steever, G. G., 1869-1874 (Offsite-box 10, Folder 16)
    - Letters received: Surget, James, 1869-1878 (Offsite-box 10, Folder 17)
    - Letters received: Tallant & Co., 1875-1876 (Offsite-box 10, Folder 18)
    - Letters received: Tallant & Co., 1876-1878 (Offsite-box 10, Folder 19)
    - Letters received: Thompson, Withers, Woodward, 1867-1868 (Offsite-box 10, Folder 20)
    - Letters received: Thompson and Woodward, 1868-1869, 1871 (Offsite-box 10, Folder 21)
    - Letters received: Withers, J. N., 1868-1872 (Offsite-box 10, Folder 22)
    - Letters received: Wolfe, Jacob, 1868-1870 (Offsite-box 10, Folder 23)
    - Letters received: Wolfe, S. S., 1870-1872 (Offsite-box 10, Folder 24)
    - Letters received: Wolff, S., 1866-1868 (Offsite-box 10, Folder 25)
    - Letters received: Woodward, G. A., 1868-1869 (Offsite-box 10, Folder 26)
    - Letters received: Woodward & Law, 1871-1872 (Offsite-box 10, Folder 27)
    - Letters sent: A - Z, 1865, 1866, 1869-1877 (Offsite-box 10, Folder 28)
    - Letters sent: Atwood, Thomas, 1865 (Offsite-box 10, Folder 29)
    - Telegrams sent: "Telegrams" [Original Housed w/ "Fragile Documents"], [1870-1880] (Offsite-box 10, Folder 30)
    - "Letter Book", 1838-1841 (Offsite-box 59, Volume 1)
    - "J. R. Aiken", 1870-1876 (Offsite-box 59, Volume 2)
    - "Special. Bills. 250. Page", 1873-1874 (Offsite-box 70, Volume 48)
    - "Telegrams", 1875-1876 (Offsite-box 59, Volume 3)
    - Private Telegraphic Code for Correspondence between Messrs. Leverich & Co. New York and Lesesne & Wells 1870 (Offsite-box 56)
    - Code Book, undated (Offsite-box 56)
  - Subseries 2: Charles P. Leverich, 1829-1874
    The inclusive dates for the material pertaining to Charles P. Leverich are 1829 to 1874. Most of the correspondents are southern businessmen or planters and business affairs play prominently in their letters. Correspondents include A. McWilliams, who wrote from Camperdown, a plantation in Louisiana, and A. D. Shepard of Franklin, Louisiana. Both of these men wrote mainly about sugar and cotton. C. A. F. Rondeau, of New Orleans, wrote on behalf of the Louisiana State Bank. Letters from William E. Leverich of New Orleans have to do with Leverich & Co.'s Louisiana interests in general. Letters from clients of Charles P. Leverich, in his capacity as a cotton factor, include those from Stephen Duncan of Natchez, Mississippi, and William J. Minor, also of Natchez.
    Charles P. Leverich's answers to some of this correspondence can be found in his letter books, which date from 1839 to 1844, 1841 to 1845, and 1853 to 1854. In the letter books, he concerns himself primarily with financial affairs and international trade, and only to a lesser extent addresses specific dealings in Southern commodities. Much of the unbound material addressed to Charles P. Leverich dates from the period 1860-1868; his letter books date from an earlier period. Thus, the persons and firms represented in the letter books are not always the same as those represented in the loose correspondence. Persons who appear frequently in the letter books are L. Millandon, J.H. Leverich and P.J. Palfrey of New Orleans, John S. Riddle and Charles P. Relf of Philadelphia, and Newton Mercer of Natchez.
    Virtually every Southern correspondent of Charles P. Leverich commented on the political events of 1860-1861. The majority of material in the Leverich Papers concerning the election of Abraham Lincoln and the Secession Crisis is in this subseries.
    - Letters received: A - M, 1839, 1857-1867, 1870-1871, undated (Offsite-box 11, Folder 1)
    - Letters received: N - Z, 1858-1861, 1865, 1872 (Offsite-box 11, Folder 2)
    - Letters received: Duncan, S., 1858 (Offsite-box 11, Folder 3)
    - Letters received: Duncan, S., 1859 (Offsite-box 11, Folder 4)
    - Letters received: Leverich. A. I., 1869 (Offsite-box 11, Folder 5)
    - Letters received: Leverich, Charles D., 1860, 1867, 1873 (Offsite-box 11, Folder 6)
    - Letters received: Leverich, Henry S., 1868-1871, undated (Offsite-box 11, Folder 7)
    - Letters received: Leverich, William E., 1859 (Offsite-box 11, Folder 8)
    - Letters received: Leverich, William E., 1860 (Offsite-box 11, Folder 9)
    - Letters received: Leverich, William E., 1861-1863 (Offsite-box 11, Folder 10)
    - Letters received: Marshall, L. R., 1860-1861 (Offsite-box 11, Folder 11)
    - Letters received: McWilliams, A., 1857-1858 (Offsite-box 11, Folder 12)
    - Letters received: McWilliams, A., 1859-1861 (Offsite-box 11, Folder 13)
    - Letters received: Mercer, William N., 1859-1861, 1865-1866 (Offsite-box 11, Folder 14)
    - Letters received: Palfrey, W. T., 1860-1861 (Offsite-box 11, Folder 15)
    - Letters received: Payne, George, 1860-1861, 1865 (Offsite-box 11, Folder 16)
    - Letters received: Porter, Annie, 1861 (Offsite-box 11, Folder 17)
    - Letters received: Porter, Mary, 1860-1861 (Offsite-box 11, Folder 18)
    - Letters received: Pringle, J. J., 1860-1861 (Offsite-box 11, Folder 19)
    - Letters received: Rondeau, C. A. F., 1856-1857 (Offsite-box 12, Folder 1)
    - Letters received: Rondeau, C. A. F., 1858 (Offsite-box 12, Folder 2)
    - Letters received: Rondeau, C. A. F., 1859-1861 (Offsite-box 12, Folder 3)
    - Letters received: Shepard, A. D., 1858-1859 (Offsite-box 12, Folder 4)
    - Letters received: Shepard, A. D., 1860-1865 (Offsite-box 12, Folder 5)
    - Letters received: Shields, G. B., 1860-1861 (Offsite-box 12, Folder 6)
    - Letters received: Smith, Homer H., 1860 (Offsite-box 12, Folder 7)
    - Letters received: Smith & Hine, 1860-1861 (Offsite-box 12, Folder 8)
    - Letters received: Stansbury, N., 1860-1861 (Offsite-box 12, Folder 9)
    - Letters received: Surget, F., 1860-1861 (Offsite-box 12, Folder 10)
    - Letters sent: A - Z, 1829, 1839, 1857-1861, undated (Offsite-box 12, Folder 11)
    - "Letter Book", 1839-1844 (Offsite-box 59, Volume 4)
    - "Letter Book", 1841-1845 (Offsite-box 60, Volume 5)
    - "Letter Book", 1853-1854 (Offsite-box 60, Volume 6)
  - Subseries 3: Henry S. Leverich, 1824-1877
    Business affairs also figure prominently in the correspondence of Henry S. Leverich, the other principal partner in Leverich & Co. The inclusive dates for this material are 1824 to 1877. Almost all the letters in the collection from before 1840 are addressed to Henry S. Leverich, as opposed to Leverich & Co. Correspondents include James Colles and Joseph Lallande, both of New Orleans, who wrote about the sugar trade in the 1820's. Peters and Millard, also of that city, concerned themselves mostly with financial matters during the following decade. The sub-series also contains correspondence from W. & J.H. Leverich, Leverich & Co.'s New Orleans counterpart. Henry S. Leverich's responses to the letters of W. & J.H. Leverich are usually addressed to one or the other of the partners in that firm, rather than to the firm as such. Most of this material is from the 1820's and 1830's. J. Oliviera & Co. of London and Madeira corresponded with Henry S. Leverich during the 1830's regarding the wine trade. Tallant & Co., in the 1870's, apprized Henry S. Leverich of the status of his stock holdings in the Western United States. Letters from other correspondents dealt with a range of mercantile pursuits. Foldered with the correspondence is a small travel diary of Henry's voyage to New Orleans on the ship Frances Fosdick, in 1826 and a one-page journal of the ship Huntsville in 1836.
    The nine letter books of Henry S. Leverich date from 1824 to 1849, with a gap between 1836 and 1838. One of the letter books is blank. Almost all of this material has to do with specific transactions in cotton, molasses, sugar, rice, tobacco or coffee. Of particular note, however, are Henry Leverich's letters from the Southern States to his brother Charles in the mid-1820's; his observations to Oliviera & Co. on the Oregon Boundary dispute, the Mexican-American War, and the tariff; and his close monitoring of the rice market during the European potato blight of 1847. Throughout, he sometimes makes passing comments on the policies of the Administrations of the period, and on political events.
    Correspondence of Edward Leverich, his wife, Annie, and George Payne, comprise three distinct but related subseries of the Correspondence series.
    - Letters received: A - P, 1827-1876, undated (Offsite-box 13, Folder 1)
    - Letters received: R - Z, 1837-1839, 1852, 1856 (Offsite-box 13, Folder 2)
    - Letters received: Colles, James, 1827-1829 (Offsite-box 13, Folder 3)
    - Letters received: Hyde, T. R., 1827-1828 (Offsite-box 13, Folder 4)
    - Letters received: Lallande, Joseph, 1826-1828 (Offsite-box 13, Folder 5)
    - Letters received: Leverich, Charles P., 1844 (Offsite-box 13, Folder 6)
    - Letters received: Leverich, Edward, 1870 (Offsite-box 13, Folder 7)
    - Letters received: Leverich, James H., 1829, 1835-1844 (Offsite-box 13, Folder 8)
    - Letters received: Leverich, W. & J. H., 1829 (Offsite-box 13, Folder 9)
    - Letters received: Leverich, William E., 1829, 1842-1844 (Offsite-box 13, Folder 10)
    - Letters received: Minor, William J., 1838-1839 (Offsite-box 13, Folder 11)
    - Letters received: Oliviera, John & Co., 1838-1839 (Offsite-box 13, Folder 12)
    - Letters received: Peters & Millard, 1838-1839 (Offsite-box 13, Folder 13)
    - Letters received: Riddle, John S., 1838-1839 (Offsite-box 13, Folder 14)
    - Letters received: Tallant & Co., 1876-1877 (Offsite-box 13, Folder 15)